Elias Renawi – CV

Name: Elias Renawi

Phone Number: 0528423617
Email: eliasrenawi23@gmail.com
LinkedIn: Elias Renawi LinkedIn
GitHub: Elias Renawi GitHub

Summary

Software Engineer at Galil Software with over 1 year of experience, specializing in React, Typescript, Next.js, and Python Flask. Software Engineering graduate from ORT Braude College with a B.Sc. in Software Engineering and a GPA of 83. Highly organized, self-motivated individual with a strong desire to learn new technologies and gain valuable experience. Seeking a junior software engineering position to further expand skills and contribute to innovative projects.

Work Experience

April 2023 - Present: Galil Software, Nazareth, IL

- Front-End Developer specializing in React, Typescript, and Next.js.
- Developed and maintained web applications, ensuring high performance and responsiveness.
- Collaborated with back-end developers and UX/UI designers to improve the user experience.
- Acquired proficiency in Python Flask framework.

2021 -2022: ORT Braude College

Tutor for first year student in math courses.

Education

2017 - 2022: ORT Braude College of Engineering

- B.Sc., Software Engineering Graduate. GPA: 83
- Grades
 - o Data Structures: 83
 - o Computer Networks :98
 - O Object Oriented Programming (java):96
 - o Architecture and Computer Structure: 88
 - Data Security and Cryptology :85
 - o Real Time Operating Systems :82.

• Projects:

- o **Final project:** <u>Similar Text Search Technology</u>" (Part of research about the Similarity between 2 Large texts and using the text rank algorithm to extract the most significant sentences in a text and text processing. Implemented using C# .NET framework)
- o Braude system for employees and students. (Client -Server, JavaFx, JDBC, MySQL, OCSF).
- Secure Email Exchange (Using Serpent and OFB model, El Gamal signature, implemented in python)
- website For Insurance Company (Node.js, React.js, Bootstrap, MYSQL and Heroku)

Training:

Course of 225 hours for Full stack Engineers include the following topics:

Html/css/js ,MongoDB,Express(.js), React(.js) ,Node(.js)

• **Kav Mashve**: Association's business club program. The program included get familiarity with various high-tech organizations and preparation for Job Interviews

Skills:

- JAVA Developer C -Specialist C++ Python Flask MATLAB C#. NET Eclipse
- Visual Studio PyCharm PostgreSQL MySQL TypeScript Node.JS Next.JS
- Teamwork Team Building •Advanced problem-solving skills •Project Organization skills

Languages

• Arabic – mother tongue | English – fluent | Hebrew – fluent